We've all heard of comfort zones in
relation to not wanting to practice,
laziness, or being scared for change and
growth. But a comfort zone can also show
up in a sneaky way during your matches.
It's a form of an expectation, and
that's never a good thing. If you expect
your match to go in a certain way
because that's where you believe your
levels at, then you're going to feel
uncomfortable when all of a sudden you
start playing better. You're not used to
it, and you start to overthink. Suddenly
you're focused on not making a mistake.
You're losing focus because you're in
the lead. You start making silly
mistakes you weren't making before. Or
you're losing confidence and start
doubting yourself if you can finish this
off. Being aware of this comfort zone is
a huge first step. And step two is keep
working the process. What do you need to
do in order to make good shots? That's
how you refocus your mind. Go for it.
Good luck.